It's been five days since the satellite crashed into the Akihabara Radio Building.
（レポーター）人工衛星の
墜落から５日が経過した―
秋葉原(あきはばら)のラジ館前です
Since morning, many people have gathered here to see it again,
今日も 朝から大勢の人が
見物に詰めかけていますが―
but the satellite's origin remains unknown,
放置されたままの人工衛星は
依然として国籍等不明のまま―
and it hasn't been scheduled to be be taken down.
撤去のめどは立っておりません
Mail Received
（レポーター）
ちょっと よろしいですか？
Do you have a moment?
Are you here to see the satellite?
今日は
人工衛星の見物でしょうか？
Could you tell us where you're from?
どちらから いらっしゃったのか
よろしければ…
あっ あ…
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）ハア ハア ハア…
（萌郁）はっ
ハア…
～
Butterfly
Effect's
Divergence
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）おお！
これが…
This is it?
おいしい！
It's delicious!
Miss Amane, you've never had a beef bowl?
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）阿万音氏 牛丼初めて？
No, I've only heard rumors of it.
（鈴羽）うん うわさには
聞いてたけど おいしいね
It's delicious.
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）
フンッ 生卵をかけると
もっと うまくなるぞ
It's even better if you put a raw egg on it.
If you call yourself a warrior,
貴様も戦士なら
１人で牛丼屋くらい―
you should be able to come to a beef bowl place by yourself.
入れるようにしておいたほうがいい
（鈴羽）なっ！
（鈴羽）ああ…
（橋田）あーあ
Well, Daru and I come here often.
（岡部）まっ 俺もダルも
この店には よく来る
If you invite us, we'll go with you anytime.
誘われれば いつでも
つきあうかんな
（橋田）あーっ 思い出したお
この前 オカリンの牛皿
I just remembered!
Last time, I had to pay for Okarin's meal.
僕が立て替えたんだった
そんなことも あったかもしれんな
It's possible that happened, yes.
It's not just possible! It happened!
“あったかも”じゃなくて
あったよ！
Give me back my money!
返してよ お金
Sadly, I don't have any on me today.
（岡部）あいにく今日は
持ち合わせがない
俺だ
It's me.
至急 スイス銀行の口座に
金を振り込んでくれ
Transfer the funds to my Swiss bank account.
What?
なんだと？
機関がジュネーブのサーバーに―
The Organization hacked into the Geneva servers?
No cell phones.
（岡部）クラッキングを？
（店員）携帯禁止
How terrible...
（岡部）クソ なんということだ
Um, he's just pretending.
（橋田）あの カッコだけですよ
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）トゥットゥルー
鈴(すず)さんも一緒だったんだ
So you were with them too, Suzu?
It was time for my lunch break.
（鈴羽）ちょうど
お昼の休憩だったから
もう少し早ければ
一緒に食べられたのにね
If you came a bit earlier, you could've joined us.
Then, do you want to go all together tomorrow?
（橋田）じゃあ あしたの昼は
みんなで行く？
This time Okarin will—
今度は オカリンのおごりで…
What?
（岡部）なんだと？
機関の妨害工作で―
The Organization's sabotaging the process,
サーバーの復旧に１週間かかる？
and it'll take a week to bring the servers back online?
（まゆり）あっ 紅莉栖(くりす)ちゃんだ
It's Kurisu!
あっ
（岡部）おう 助手
昨日は ゆっくり休めたか？
Assistant, did you get any sleep?
Don't call me "assistant."
（牧瀬(まきせ)紅莉栖）“助手”って言うな
うん？
（岡部）うん？
Hey, part-timer.
（天王寺裕吾(てんのうじゆうご)）おい バイト
昼メシ済んだら とっとと働け
If you're done with lunch, get back to work.
What's with her?
（紅莉栖）何なの？
A round table?
（まゆり）円卓会議？
Indeed.
（岡部）うむ
（橋田）なんぞ それ
What's that?
A meeting of lab members.
（岡部）ラボメンによる
ミーティングだ
Have we ever had one before?
そんなん やったことあったっけ？
Do you even own a round table?
そもそも円卓なんか
どこにあるのよ？
Not a physical one,
実物はない
だが我らラボメンの―
but the true round table lies within all lab members' hearts, right?
心の中にはある　そうだろう？
“そうだろう”じゃなかろうが
Whether it's true or not,
don't put anything weird in my heart.
勝手に人の心の中に
変なもの持たせないで
Do you think there's one in Mayushii's heart too?
まゆしぃの心の中にもあるかな
Yes, of course.
（岡部）ああ あるさ
Really?
そっかー よかった
でも円卓ってなあに？
Yay!
But what's a round table?
Why a round table?
…ってか なんで円卓？
アーサー王？
Are you supposed to be King Arthur?
I'm only a temporary lab member, anyway.
（紅莉栖）そもそも私は
ラボメンといっても期間限定だし
At any rate...
（岡部）とにかく！
円卓会議だ
it's time for a round table.
まゆりにも
俺たちの置かれた状況を―
We need to tell Mayuri about the current situation.
伝えておく必要がある
Situation?
状況って？
And so,
（岡部）…というわけで
ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)を出し抜くために
我々は一刻も早く―
in order to defeat SERN, we must perfect
the time machine functions of the Phone Microwave (name subject to change)
「電話レンジ（仮）(かっこかり)」の
タイムマシン機能を―
as soon as possible.
完璧なものにしなくてはならない
（まゆり）えー まゆしぃには
難しすぎて よく分からないのです
This is too hard for Mayushii to understand!
Just know that SERN is evil.
とにかくＳＥＲＮは
悪だということだ
But how do we perfect it?
（橋田）うーん だけど
「電話レンジ（仮）」を完璧にって
We've succeeded in sending messages to the past, right?
僕ら メールを過去に送る実験には
成功してね？
Only twice!
（岡部）たったの２回だけだ
And we don't know what conditions trigger the phenomenon.
しかも どのようなときに
その現象が発生するか―
まだ分かっていない
うーん この前の実験だと―
From what we observed last time,
it only occurs when there's electricity.
放電現象が起きたときだけ
送れたお
（岡部）うん
That's right!
あっ そうだ！
Did you figure something out?
（紅莉栖）何か分かったの？
（岡部）いや
No.
“過去へ送れるメール”では
言いにくい
"Emails Sent to the Past" is too long.
First, we need to find a name for them.
まずは 名前をつけるところから
始めようではないか
はあ？ またカッコつけ？
Another failed attempt to sound cool?
（岡部）“また”とか言うな！
Don't say "another"!
Do you dare mock the great Hououin...
この鳳凰院凶真(ほうおういんきょうま)を
バカにしている…
You'll just give it a stupid name, anyway.
どうせヘンテコな名前を
付けたいだけでしょ
How rude!
（岡部）失敬な ならば発表しよう
Then I'll tell you.
I've found the perfect name for the act of sending emails back in time...
俺は この過去へ送れるメール
という現象について―
こう名付けた　その名も―
I call it "Nostalgia Drive"!
ノスタルジアドライブ！
You write it with the kanji for "journey crossing over time,"
ちなみに 時を超えた
“郷愁への旅路”と書き―
but you read it "Nostalgia Drive."
ノスタルジアドライブと読ませる
分かりにく 却下
Too complicated.
Rejected.
貴様！ 助手の分際で
却下できる権限があると思って…
You!
Don't think you have the authority to reject—
なら 多数決にする？
Then let's have a vote.
Who agrees with "Nostalgia Drive"?
ノスタルジアドライブに賛成の人
（岡部）えっ
Not you too, Mayuri? Daru?
裏切ったな まゆり ダル！
I think Kurisu is right.
紅莉栖ちゃんの
言うとおりだと思うよ
Mayushii can't remember a long name like that.
まゆしぃは そんな長い名前
覚えられません
厨二病(ちゅうにびょう)すぎだろ 常考(じょうこう)
It sounds like something invented by a nerdy teenager.
We should focus on making it easy to understand.
（紅莉栖）
分かりやすさを重視すべきね
Since it's an email going back in time,
時をさかのぼるメールだから
遡行メールでいいんじゃない？
we could call it "Email That Flies Against Time."
（まゆり）“遡行”ってなあに？
What does "flies against time" mean?
（岡部）ちっとも
分かりやすくないではないか
That's not easy to understand at all.
（橋田）
ここは　時をかけるメールの
一択だろ 常考
It should be "The Email That Leapt Through Time."
That's a bit formal.
（岡部）
少し表現が固いな言いにくい
Hard to say, too.
You don't get to say that.
（紅莉栖）あんたが言うな
（橋田）オカリンのノスタルジア
何とかだって長いじゃんか
Your "Nostalgia Whatsit" was long too!
（岡部）
ロマンがあればいいのだ ロマンが
It's romantic! If it's romantic, it's okay!
（橋田）
じゃ 略して“ときかけ”で
So we can shorten it to Time-Leap.
Then we don't know what leapt through time!
（岡部）それでは
何が 時をかけるのか分からん
Is it an email? A girl? Maybe a banana?
メールなのか 少女なのか―
それともバナナなのか
（まゆり）トゥットゥルー
まゆしぃも思いついたよ
あのね…
Mayushii has an idea!
Um... "Back to the Email"!
バック トゥ ザ メール
That would be going back to the email, not back in time,
（岡部）直訳すると
“メールに戻る”意味不明だ
which doesn't make sense.
（まゆり）
じゃあ デロリアンメール
Then "DeLorean Mail"!
（岡部）ますます分からんわ！
That makes even less sense!
Hey...
（紅莉栖）ねえ
（岡部）あ？
もう いっそのこと略して
Ｄメールでいいんじゃない？
Why don't we just shorten it to "D-mail"?
（岡部）なっ
ああ それいいね
I like that.
Okay, it's decided then.
（橋田）じゃっ 決定ということで
（岡部）それでは これより―
We will now begin the experiments with D-mail (name subject to change).
「Ｄメール（仮）」の
実験を開始する
We can also cut the "(name subject to change)."
（紅莉栖）
“（仮）”も略す方向で
The operation is called "Operation Urd."
（岡部）作戦名は
オペレーションウルドだ
We don't need that either.
（紅莉栖）それも要らない
But we don't know what it takes to send a D-mail
（橋田）だけどＤメールの
発生条件 分かってないじゃん
or what it's got to do with electricity.
放電現象との関係も不明だし
フフフフッ それをこれから
確認しようというのだ
That's what we're going to find out.
I, Hououin Kyouma, have an idea.
この鳳凰院凶真に １つ仮説がある
俺たちは 最も単純にして
最も決定的な条件を見落としていた
We forgot the simplest and most important condition!
Which is...
すなわち…
the time it occurred!
発生時刻だ！
最初のＤメールは12時から13時
２回目は18時頃に発生している
The first D-mail was sent between 12:00 and 13:00.
The second occurred around 18:00.
If we attempt to replicate it at those times,
つまり その２つの時間帯に
実験することで―
we'll succeed.
再現が可能
Probably.
…かもしれない
That sounds too easy.
（橋田）いくらなんでも
単純すぎだろ 常考
It's worth a shot.
（岡部）試してみる価値はある
Mayuri, the banana!
まゆり バナナを！
うーん まゆしぃのバナナ
ずいぶん減ったね
Mayushii's running low on bananas.
Do we have to put the banana in?
バナナまで入れる必要あるの？
（橋田）バナナまで入れる
"Put the banana in"!
Daru, not now.
ダル 今は控えろ
I want to see if it turns into jelly.
ゼリーマンになるかどうかの
確認のためだ
Now, assistant,
さあ 助手 早くバナナを中へ
put the banana inside.
（橋田）バナナを中へ？
"Put the banana inside..."
Enough, you pervert!
（紅莉栖）
いいかげんにしろ この変態！
I'm sorry.
ごめんね あとで新しいバナナ
買ってくるから
I'll buy you a new banana later.
Really?
本当？
I'm so happy!
うれしいな
オカリンやダルくんはね―
Okarin and Daru never buy me any.
ちっとも買ってきてくれないのです
Geez, you two...
（紅莉栖）ホントにもう
（紅莉栖）あっ 痛たたたっ
Ow!
（岡部）ドジっ子アピールはよせ
Being clumsy isn't cute.
（紅莉栖）しとらんわ！
The heck?
うう
痛いの痛いの 飛んでいけー
Pain, pain, go away!
（紅莉栖）サンクス まゆり
Thanks, Mayuri.
（岡部）そこ！ いつまでも
百合(ゆり)フィールドを作っていないで
Stop making a Lesbomagnetic Field and prepare the D-mail.
Ｄメールの準備を！
Yeah, yeah.
（紅莉栖）はいはい
Is 120 seconds okay for the time?
（橋田）
時間設定は120秒でオーケー？
（岡部）うむ
Indeed.
オペレーションウルド 開始！
Begin Operation Urd!
今だ！
Now!
フハハハハッ
来た 来たぞー！
It's here.
It's here!
（橋田）おおっ
（岡部）バナナは？
（紅莉栖･まゆり）あっ
Where's the banana?
It's a gel-bana!
（まゆり）ゲルバナになったね
（橋田）おおっ
（岡部）フハハハハッ
I've solved it at last.
ついに解明したぞ
やはり俺の予想どおり―
As I thought, time was the D-mail's missing factor!
Ｄメールの発生条件は
時間だったのだ
Nice job, Okabe.
（紅莉栖）やるわね 岡部
あまりに単純で気づかなかった
I didn't realize it was so simple.
Does it bother you?
悔しいのか？
Still, I respect you for having the guts to admire me so closely.
それでも俺に賛辞を送る
その姿勢は 評価してやろう
フハッ フハッ
Anyway, did the D-mail arrive?
（紅莉栖）
それよりＤメールは届いてる？
（岡部）うむ 成功だ
It did.
受信日時は５日前
It says it was sent five days ago.
Did you send two messages, Miss Makise?
牧瀬氏 ２通送った？
No, just one.
ううん １通だけ
It was split into two messages.
２通に分割されてる
By the way, what does this message mean?
ちなみに この文章の意味は？
えっ？
Look it up yourself.
自分で調べれば
Come to think of it,
（橋田）そういえばさ
このあいだのＤメールも―
the last D-mail was also split into multiple messages,
分割されて
文章は途中で切れてたよな
and some of it was lost.
And it went back in time five days too.
さかのぼった時間も
同じく５日だったし
Yeah, there must be some kind of rules for it.
ああ 何か法則性が…
あっ！
Which means that D-mail...
…ということは
あのメールは―
頭からっぽの
バカだということか！
...was calling me an empty-headed idiot?
Took you a while.
気付くの遅すぎ
Curse you, Christina. Taking advantage of a...
おのれ クリスティーナ
どさくさに紛れて…
うん？
ちょっと待て
こんなに買ってどうする？
Wait a minute. Why are you buying so much?
The only food we need is nonperishable cup ramen.
食料は保存の利く
カップめんで十分だろう
One bag of the cheap chocolate is plenty.
チョコも 徳用のが１袋あればいい
I'm celebrating our experiment's success.
だって 実験成功のお祝いだし
（岡部）いいから戻してこい
Go put it back.
Cheap-ass.
（橋田）チェッ ケチくさ
あ…
ハッ
That's right.
（岡部）そうだ 実験成功と
浮かれていたが
I was so happy about the experiment's success that I forgot.
We learned SERN's terrifying secret.
俺たちはＳＥＲＮの恐ろしい機密を
知ってしまったのだ
And I even got Mayuri involved.
まゆりまで
巻き込んでしまって―
本当によかったのか？
Was this really for the best?
（萌郁）あっ
（岡部）うん？
It's Shining Finger.
シャイニング･フィンガーでは
ないか
なんだ？
What?
さっきから何をしている
What are you doing?
You don't have your cell phone?
（萌郁）携帯 持ってないの？
The great Hououin Kyouma's cell phone is
この鳳凰院凶真の携帯は 今―
currently being used for an experiment that'll leave our names in history.
人類史に名を残す
偉大な実験に使用中のため―
（岡部）ここにはない
（橋田）お待た～と…
It's not here.
I'm back.
Huh?
（橋田）おっ おっ オカリン
（岡部）うん？
O-O-Okarin!
Who's that erotic...
そちらのエロい… あっ いや
セクシーな３次元の女性は―
I mean sexy... 3D girl?
どなたでありますか？
（岡部）ふむ 紹介しよう
I'll introduce you.
This is Shining Finger, Kiryuu Moeka.
シャイニング･フィンガー
桐生萌郁だ
I-It's nice to meet you, Kiry—
よっ よろしく桐生氏…
Even I once had hope for the 3D world.
３次元に希望を持っていた時期が
僕にもありますた
（鈴羽）あっ ちーっす
Yo!
ひょっとして さっきから
愉快なことしてる？
Are you guys doing something fun?
（岡部）いかにも
Indeed.
We are doing experiments that'll leave our names in hist—
俺たちは 人類史に
名を残すであろう実験を…
名を残すのは いいけどさ
Leaving your names is fine...
but the boss is really pissed off.
店長が すっごく
イライラしてるわけ
He says the vibrations from the second story are really bad.
２階からの振動が すごくってさ
"I'll raise your rent 10,000 yen!"
“家賃１万円アップするぞ
コラッ”とか何とか
Something like that.
（橋田･岡部）なっ
１万…
10,000 yen?
Okay, leave this to me.
よし ここは俺に任せろ
Tell my assistant to stop the experiments for the moment, Daru.
ダルは助手に しばらく
実験をやめるよう伝えてくれ
Roger.
了解 あんた
今 最高に輝いてるよ
You're shining like never before...
Is Makise Kurisu still there?
牧瀬紅莉栖もまだいるの？
あ？ ああ そういえば
さっきも じっと見てたな
Oh, yeah. You were staring at her back there, weren't you?
So, what happened earlier? What's your deal with her?
この前といい
なぜ やつにこだわる？
Did something happen in the past?
過去に何かあったのか？
Nothing in the past, no.
（鈴羽）過去には 何もない
（岡部）そう あれは８歳の夏―
Yes, it was the summer when we were eight.
ミシシッピの河川敷で
逃げ出したアカミミ…
And on the dry riverbed of the Mississippi, your red-eared slider ran away...
（鈴羽）何もないって！
この前が初見
It was nothing!
I saw her for the first time earlier!
Anyway, you should go see the boss.
それより 早く店長に
謝りに行ったほうがいいよ
うう…
What are you doing upstairs?
（天王寺）お前ら いったい
上で何やってんだ？
It's been shaking like an earthquake.
さっきから何度も
派手に揺らしやがって
We're performing an experiment that'll rewrite scientific history.
実は人類の科学史を塗り替える―
世紀の実験中でしてね
しかし ご安心を
But don't worry.
We won't do any more today—
今日は もうこれ以上は あっ…
くっ やめろと言ったのに ううっ
I said stop!
うう…
What are you doing?
何をしてるか
実験は中止だと言ったろう！
I said stop!
最後に もう１回だけって
牧瀬氏が…
Miss Makise said to let her do it just one more time.
I sent you a message. Did you see it?
（紅莉栖）
メールしたんだけど見てない？
Of course not!
（岡部）見られるわけなかろうが
（紅莉栖）５日も前に忠告したのに
I warned you five days ago...
Don't mess with me—
（岡部）ふざけるな！
あっ あとなんか 実験以外でも
オカリンの携帯 何度も鳴ってたよ
Oh, when we weren't doing the experiments,
your phone went off a bunch of times.
うん？
Really!
Sorry!
Are you maybe
How've you been?
?
Well?
Sorry!
Are you maybe
How've you been?
?
Well?
Hey?
Hey
How've you been? Okabe
Well?
Find out anything about the IBN 5100 ?
くうっ なんで直接言わんか！
Why didn't she just ask me directly?
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
I don't know,
（紅莉栖）なんだか分からないけど
カルシウム足りてないみたいね
but he probably isn't getting enough calcium.
（岡部）誰のせいだ
Whose fault is that?
（紅莉栖）
まっ データは十分取れたし―
Well, I got plenty of data,
and I pretty much figured out the rules for how the D-mail works.
Ｄメールの法則についても
大体 分かったからいいけど
What?
（岡部）なにっ？
Each second on the timer represents one hour back in time.
（紅莉栖）Ｄメールが
さかのぼる時間については―
タイマーの１秒が
現実の１時間に相当する
One hundred twenty seconds turns into five days.
120秒で５日
それで５日前ってわけ
（橋田）いつ送るか調整できるの
発見したのは すごくね？
It's amazing that she figured out how to control how far it goes back, isn't it?
（岡部）だが 送れる文字数は
英文で最大36文字―
But the maximum amount of information that can be sent back is 36 English characters
or 18 Japanese characters.
日本文で18文字だ
It's too small.
少なすぎる
改善したいところだな
I'd like to fix that.
I'm sure you can't send anything too big or send too much.
きっと 大きなものとか
たくさんは送れないんだね
あっ もしかして
そのカーブブラックホールが…
Maybe it's that Curb black hole...
Kerr black hole, indeed.
カーブラックホールね
The hole's too tight!
そのブラックホールの穴が
きついんだよ
あっ まゆ氏 今の言葉
もう１度 穴のところから…
Can you repeat that, Mayushii?
The part about the hole?
Shut up, pervert!
（紅莉栖）やめろ 変態！
Anyhow, we can work out the details later,
とにかく 詳細な検証は
明日以降に行う
but I'll say this:
だが これだけは宣言しておこう
August 2, 2010,
2010年８月２日は―
人類史にとって 永遠に
記憶に残る日になるであろう
is a day that mankind will remember forever,
for us, the Future Gadget Lab,
なぜなら この日
我ら未来ガジェット研究所は―
has succeeded in developing humanity's
人類史上初の
タイムマシン開発に―
成功したからであーる！
first time machine!
It's not the first one, right?
（橋田）初じゃなくね？
ＳＥＲＮに先越されてたし
SERN beat us.
We didn't "develop" it, anyway.
（紅莉栖）そもそも
開発したとは言えない
It was all coincidence.
偶然 使えるようになっただけ
（岡部）どいつもこいつも―
All of you, disrespecting my great declaration...
俺の 堂々たる宣言に
敬意すら払わんとは
（まゆり）でも オカリン
（岡部）え？
But Okarin...
I'm glad your experiments worked.
実験がウマくいって よかったね
はあ…
Where am I?
ここは…
あっ ああ
うっ うわあ
ああっ
You're not moving.
（紅莉栖）あんたは
移動なんてしていない
Time and space have switched places here.
ここでは 空間と時間が
入れ代わっている
The event horizon?
（岡部）イベントホライゾンか
You can't move through space,
（紅莉栖）あんたは
空間を移動することはできない
時間だけが 延々と
引き延ばされている
and time is extended forever.
One second of your time is an eternity to me.
あんたの１秒が 私には永遠となる
Is the edge of the universe running away?
（岡部）宇宙の果てが逃げている
No, that's not it, but something's expanding.
いや 違う 引き延ばされている
What is?
何が？ 宇宙が？ 俺が？
The universe?
Me?
You mustn't look back.
（紅莉栖）振り返ってはいけない
永遠は無限ではない
Eternity isn't infinity.
Even if time appears to extend toward eternity,
永遠に向かって
時間が引き延ばされようとも―
an end still exists.
終わりは 存在する
（岡部）ハッ
When will it be one second later?
１秒後は いつやってくる？
Look forward.
（紅莉栖）
前を向いて　たどり着いて
Reach the end.
You mustn't turn back.
振り返ってはいけない
（岡部）あっ うん…
That emailing freak again?
またメール魔か
相変わらずの しつこさ
Her persistence...
You there?
It's dark
Wake up
I'm here
You asleep?
Does it bug you?
Sorry for yesterday
Moeka
"Sorry for yesterday."
"Can I come see you?"
“これから
そっちへ行っていい？”
まだ寝てるとは考えないのか？
It didn't occur to you that I was asleep?
I'm here
At least answer me.
Or are you pretending to not be there?
Moeka
Wake up
Were you asleep?
Moeka
I was asleep!
もしかしなくても寝てた
うん？ なんだと
It's dark
I'm coming up the stairs right now.
Moeka
What?
（岡部）ハア ハア
（岡部）あっ？
I'm outside.
I'll knock. If you're there, respond.
Moeka
（萌郁）ハッ
あ…
You said I could come see you,
right?
Moeka
Why use your cell phone?
なぜメールする？
目の前にいるのに
I'm right here.
見ないぞ 直接言え
I'm not looking at it. Just say it.
I can show you, but I didn't think you'd come this early.
見せるのはいいが
こんな朝っぱらから来るとは―
I get it!
あっ そうか 貴様
本当の狙いは この俺の取材だな！
You really want to interview me, don't you?
Why don't you talk?
なぜ しゃべらない
I see... So that's it.
なるほど そういうことか
You're terrified of Mad Scientist Hououin Kyouma's sinister aura!
この俺 狂気の
マッドサイエンティスト―
鳳凰院凶真の邪悪なるオーラを
恐れているのだな
フハハハハッ
It's easier to send emails...
メールのほうが 気楽だから
So, show me the IBN 5100.
ＩＢＮ5100 見せてほしいの
（岡部）いいだろう
Very well.
But I'm just showing it to you.
しかし 見せるだけだ
そして 見たら帰るのだ
Once you've seen it, leave!
Is that all right?
それでいいか？
（岡部）こいつ もしかして
ただのレトロＰＣマニアか？
Is she just a retro-PC fan?
Let me take a picture
Moeka
（岡部）う…
But not my face.
俺の顔以外だ もし撮ったら
お前の口封じをするしか…
If you photograph my face,
I'll have to silence you forever...
Please!
I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?
I'd be happy if you'd help me
carry it.
Moeka
"I'd like you to loan it to me, okay?"
"I'd be happy if you'd help me carry..."
Why am I suddenly lending it to you?
なぜ 貸すのが
前提になっとるのだ？
And if you really want me to loan it to you, then look at me and say it.
それに 本当に貸してほしいのなら
こっちを向いて直接話せ
Will you loan it to me?
貸してくれるの？
残念ながらダメだ
Sadly, no.
I'm only borrowing it myself.
そもそも 俺も
一時的に借りただけだ
When I'm done,
使い終わったら
元の所有者に返すことになる
I have to return it to its original owner.
Its original owner?
元の所有者って？
Yanabayashi Shrine.
柳林(やなばやし)神社だ
（橋田）グーテンモルゲン
Guten Morgen.
うあ 確か昨日の桐生氏？
You're Miss Kiryuu from yesterday, right?
昨日は紹介していなかったな
I didn't introduce you yesterday, did I?
My favorite right arm, Super Haker Daru.
マイ フェイバリット
ライト アーム―
スーパーハカーのダルだ
It's "Super Hacker," man. Seriously.
（橋田）だから
スーパーハッカーだって
Anyway, I thought I'd improve the Phone Microwave a little.
あっ そうそう それより
「電話レンジ」―
ちょっと改良しようと
思うんだよね
It's currently a bit of a pain in the ass, right?
今 結構
めんどい手順が必要じゃん？
Ｄメールを過去に送るのにさ
Sending the D-mails to the past, that is.
（岡部）あっ ああ…
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
What does he mean,
"sending mails to the past"?
Moeka
（岡部）
なっ なんでもない 聞き違いだ
I-It's nothing.
You misheard.
He didn't say, "Sending emails to the past."
“過去にメールを送る”
ではなくてだな―
He said, "Sen Dingma Ils Tot Hepast,"
カ コニメ イル
オクゥール と言ったのだ
which is ancient Sumerian for "Did you eat breakfast?"
これは今は失われし
古代シュメール語で―
朝ごはん もう食べた？
の意味で…
トゥットゥルー
おはよう オカリン
Good morning, Okarin!
Can Mayushii prepare the fried chicken before your time machine experiment?
タイムマシン実験する前に―
まゆしぃの から揚げ
温めさせてほしいな
Okabe.
（紅莉栖）
岡部 タイムマシンのことで
１つ思いついたんだが…
I had an idea about the time machine.
（岡部）うう…
It's me.
俺だ マズいことになった
This is bad.
No.
いや そうじゃない
８号機の情報が第三者に漏れた
Information about #8 has been leaked to a third party.
（岡部）ああ 分かってる…
（紅莉栖）どういう状況？
Ah, I get it. I'll do something about it.
What's going on?
僕たち全員 華麗にスルー？
He's totally ignoring all three of us?
Depending on the situation I'll have to
seal their mouths to keep them in check.
…食い止める
We can't let the Organization find—
通話中にメールを送るな！
Don't email me while I'm on the phone!
（萌郁）ひょっとして…
Could that be...
えっ
うん？
It can't be
It can't be FB?
"FB"?
ＦＢ？ あん？
分かった こうなったら
すべてを話そう
Very well. I'll tell you everything.
秘密を知られたからには
しかたがない
Since you've found out, there's nothing else I can do.
Kiryuu Moeka,
桐生萌郁　貴様は今日から
ラボメンナンバー００５だ！
from now on, you're Lab Member 005!
（紅莉栖）ええっ？
（橋田）おお
（岡部）フッ
～